## Kat McLaren

Cybersecurity and IT professional with experience in cloud security, system administration, and technical support. Skilled in AWS and Wiz security best practices, process automation with Python, and compliance improvement through user collaboration. Strong documentation and technical communication skills to support security initiatives and ensure clarity across teams.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## **Cloud Security Student Assistant**

October 2024 - Present

Lawrence Berkeley National Lab, Cybersecurity - Berkeley, CA

- Gaining hands-on experience in Wiz and AWS security best practices to improve cloud security posture
- Identifying and resolving AWS security issues through direct communication and collaboration with users
- Automating bulk email communication by developing a Python script integrated with SendGrid to send 70+ emails efficiently
- Designing and executing a self-directed red team simulation in a sandbox AWS environment to evaluate the detection and alerting capabilities of Wiz and CloudTrail

#### **BCSB Student Assistant**

October 2022 - September 2024

Lawrence Berkeley National Lab, Advanced Light Source - Berkeley, CA

- Developed Python scripts for file management and machine testing
- Set up Puppet and CheckMK servers and configured agents to more easily update beamline servers with the necessary files and packages and monitor issues as they arise
- Supported my team on technical issues that arose including system administration, website management, and upgrading or adding features to existing systems
- Wrote technical documentation on the team's internal Confluence site for any new features added

## Workstation Support Student Assistant March – September 2022

Lawrence Berkeley National Lab, IT - Berkeley, CA

- Collaborated with Workstation Support to maintain secure, functional computers and ergonomically safe workspaces for Lab employees
- Provided technical support to Lab employees regarding various issues, including equipment return and processing, and computer repair or replacement
- Worked on technical projects to assist other departments including embedded IT support and cybersecurity
- Project work including lead on the evaluation of local password reset software and disk encryption software supporting a zero trust environment

#### CONTACT

- · San Francisco, CA
- · 415-676-1098
- mcLcomdata@proton.me
- · linkedin.com/in/kat-mclaren
- · portfolio.katshrimp.life

#### **SKILLS**

## Programming:

- Python (web dev and scripting)
- · Unix/Linux command line
- Puppet
- · C++
- Django
- JavaScript

#### System Administration:

- Virtual machines
- Ticketing systems
- Linux
- CheckMK
- SSL Certificates/Certificate

## Authorities

- Apache
- Database management

#### Cloud Security:

- Wiz
- · AWS/GCP
- SumoLogic
- Zeek

## Business Skills:

Writing

documentation/knowledge based articles

Customer service/de-escalation

#### **EDUCATION**

### City College of San Francisco

Associate of Sciences
Computer Networking & Information
Technology - Cybersecurity - May 2024
Computer Science - 2020 - Present

## General Assembly SF

Software Engineering
Immersive
Full-Stack Web Development - Jan 2020

### New York University

Associate of Arts Art History, Studio Art – May 2014

## **Good Tech Scholars Program**

July - August 2021

IBM - Remote

- Researched clean energy alternatives and developed a chatbot using IBM Watson Assistant API and Node.js which helped the user find solar options to decrease their carbon footprint
- Created a Cloudant database to connect to the chatbot using IBM Cloud code patterns
- Worked together as a team with the guidance of IBM mentors, created a group presentation to share our project with a panel of IBM judges

## Shift Lead, Sr. Sales Associate

January 2017 - August 2019

GameStop - New York, NY and Jersey City, NJ

- Promoted from cashier to management in 1 year and recruited to New Jersey location to manage merchandising, inventory, shipment processing, and new employee training
- Managed team day-to-day and delegated tasks amongst team members
- Achieved highest sales by a margin of over 3 thousand dollars during the 2018 holiday season

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## AWS Cloud Security Red Team Simulation (In Progress) LBNL - Cyber

- Conducting a simulated attacker scenario in a sandbox AWS account to evaluate security tool visibility (Wiz, CloudTrail) and detection coverage
- Building out a representative lab environment with typical AWS resources to replicate real-world usage
- Documenting each stage of the project, including environment setup, simulated activities, and detection results, for an internal knowledge share and presentation

### **Password Reset Project**

LBNL - IT

- Researched and tested four different applications to reset local Windows account passwords and determined which was the best for our needs
- Presented my findings in a PowerPoint presentation to the IT department and composed documentation enabling IT support team to easily use the software to create a bootable password reset USB
- Purchased an enterprise license which is now available for the IT
   Support Services team to download on the company software page
- Received a Spot Recognition Award from the IT department for my work

#### **Don't Waste Food**

#### 2020 DevWeek Hackathon

- Led a team in creating a web app that used the TomTom API to help people with extra food connect to food banks accepting donations
- As a team we created an SQL database to store user account information, and used JavaScript and React.js to incorporate the TomTom API and presented our app to a panel of judges

#### **AWARDS**

#### CCSF Dean's List

Achieved a 4.0 GPA as a full-time student — Dec 2023

## Spot Recognition Awards -Berkeley Lab

**BCSB** 

Record year of productivity with over 60,000 crystals analyzed – Dec 2023

IT - Workstation Support
Individual award for my work on
Windows password resetting software
and a group award for my assistance
with Sophos disc encryption — Sep
2022

## NextGen CyberTalent Grant

Selected for a competitive cybersecurity scholar grant for achievements in relevant classes – July 2021

#### **CERTIFICATES**

## CCSF Certificate of Achievement

Computer Programming: C++ – May 2024

## CCSF Certificate of Achievement

Cybersecurity - Dec 2023

# CCSF Certificate of Achievement

Network Security - Dec 2023

#### OTHER

- CCSF CCDC competitor since 2023
- SF Bookworms Club Founder
   2023
- LBNL Dungeons and Dragons
   Dungeon Master since 2022
- SF LGBT Center volunteer since
- BSides Conference volunteer since 2020